Romualdi, Serafino Papers 5459
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Cuba - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Correspondence to Romualdi from Hernandez in Cuba describes the political and labor situation in Cuba. Includes requests for visas to US and problems of labor leaders being arrested, etc. Other correspondence deals with ORIT-ICFTU and AFL-CIO relations to
- Cuba - Reports and Statements, 1946-1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Includes reports from within Cuba on movement for free labor and its relationship to CTAL; 1952 report of address by Francisco Aguirre (ORIT Gen. Sec.) after military coup; reports by Robert Alexander on effect of coup on Labor in Cuba; and CTC report "Fo
- Cuba - Reports and Statements, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Includes background information on history of Cuban labor mov't.; speech by Mariada Arensberg on her experiences in Cuba; Statement & proposals made by Fidel Castro, Raul Chibas and Felipe Pazos; ORIT visit to Cuba and its, report; reprints of articles r
- Cuba - Reports and Statements, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Includes report from ILO Conference in Havana; report by Romualdi on the impact of Castro in Central America; CTC report about its activities; Research Institute report on Cuba (Aug. 1, 1959); notes on a meeting in 1959 between representatives of the AFL
- Cuba - Notes, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Notes on Pellon, Knight, etc. on discussion during AFL-CIO-CTC meeting
- Cuba - Clippings and publications (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Guiana, British, 1953-1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Includes "The Facts about B.G." (1953) published by USA and deals with deterring Communist Coups and influence in gov't.; "The Communist Martyr Makers" Account of free trade unionism in B.G. in 1964; Excerpts from various publications concerning B.G.
- Guiana, Dutch, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Contains Romualdi's report on his trip to Dutch Guiana in (1952)
- Haiti Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Includes correspondence. w/Earl Brennan concerning the political situation in Haiti and support for Jumelle (1956-58); copy of letter from Jumelle to Brennan concerning rigging of 1957 elections and possible US support; letter to Brennan concerning Duvali
- Haiti - Reports - Releases - Clippings, 1949-1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Includes report on the organization of the committee of trade union coordination of Haiti (1951); newspaper report of attempted revolution; 1956 report on Trade Union Mov't.; report on Organisation of Committee for Trade Union Coordination (1951) ;(1949)
- Honduras Correspondence, 1955-1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Memo to Paul Reed concerning A. Jauregui's visit to Honduras (1955); Letter to Jauregui from Jose Cubas Gross concerning ORIT relation in Honduras and creditability of Alfredo Giardino (1955); correspondence. w/Ramon Villeda Moral. dealing with his being
- Honduras Statements and Reports, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  News release concerning settlement of United Fruit Co. Strike and the condition of union movement (1954); report from Honduras (1954) on strikes; confidential memorandum on Honduras concerning Communist labor movement activities (1956); other reports.
- Honduras Clippings (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Jamaica Correspondence, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Correspondence w/Florizel Glass pole (Jamaican Sec. Labor) dealing with the Jamaican Labor Recruiting program (Farm Work Program). (1955)
- Jamaica Reports, 1938-1953 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Includes memo concerning history of labor movement in Jamaica since 1938; report by Robert Alexander on Organized Labor in Jamaica (1953); misc. reports
- Jamaica Clippings (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Mexico Correspondence, 1946-1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Correspondence w/Victor Serge concerning Mexican Labor Organization's, AFL & CIT Memo on Mexican Conference (1950); Corres. with Jose Antonio Genit concerning weakness of democratic forces in Mexico, communist control of press and murder of Negreiros (195
- Mexico Reports and Statements, 1951-1955 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Includes Declaration of Conferencia del Hemisferio Occidental meeting in Mexico(l95l) as well as minutes & reports of that meeting; memo concerning meeting with Fidel Velazquez, Secretary General CTM, Mitchell and Romualdi (1953); Romualdi travel notes to
- Mexico Clippings, 1951-1955 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Nicaragua Correspondence, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Corres. with Cesar Pazos Alvarez discussing Somoza's policies and plans (1956); Corres. w/Donald Easum (American Embassy) concerning Romualdi's trip to Nicaragua (1956); Corres. w/Tulio Garcia concerning labor situation in Nicaragua and Nicaragua-Honduras
- Nicaragua Reports and Articles, 1954-1959 (Box 5, Folder 14a)
  Romualdi notes on Nicaraguan visit(l954); Romualdi report on Nicaragua (1956); Federation of United Transport Workers of Nicaragua statement espousing President Somoza's virtue(l954); Romualdi's accusations against President Armas, president of Guatemala
- Panama and Canal Zone - Correspondence, 1948-1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Corres. with Luis Alejandro Cuellar (UNSO) concerning AFL trip to Panama (1948); correspondence. dealing with arrangements for Romualdi's trip to United Fruit Co. plantation in Panama(l955); Newspaper accounts of Romualdi's arrest(l955); memo to Meany re
- Panama Reports, 1949-1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Report to AFL Executive Council for Committee to study labor conditions on Canal Zone(l949); unsigned report on Panama (1954) concerning trade union mov't. and reasons for its slow growth; Romualdi report on his visit to Panama (1956) including discussion
- Panama Clippings, 1947-1958 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Paraguay - Correspondence, 1950-1966 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Includes letter to Meany from William Sanders of OAS concerning Meany's request re democratic free labor in Paraguay (1959); letter to Meany from CPT in exile re their fight against communism (1960); report to Jauregui concerning educational program (ORI
- Paraguay Reports, 1954-1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Reports on Paraguay from Maradiaga (1954) and list of names of labor leaders and background on them (1966)
- Paraguay Clippings (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Peru Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Includes correspondence. w/ George Meany concerning contacts and labor situation in Peru (1946); letter to Nelson Rockefeller concerning Haya de la Torre visit to U.S. (1946); Other correspondence. in relation to Haya de la Torre's visit; correspondence.
- Peru Correspondence, 1951-1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Correspondence concerning Peru's union situation w/Leopoldo Pita, and various other correspondence. w/ Manual Seone (51), Victorio Casagrandi(51), Cesar A. Carrillo Salinas (5l0, Juan F. Moya (51)5 Luis Aliaga concerning his son's wish to be schooled in U
- Peru Reports and Statements, 1949-1957 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Report by Manuel Seoane on La Junta Military del Peru and the adulteration of the truth (1949); Confidential report on present political situation in Latin America and in Peru in particular with reference to Communism and US Latin America Policy(l949); M
- Clippings Peru, 1950-1963 (Box 6, Folder 3a)
- Peru - Victor Raul Haya de la Torre Corres., 1948-1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Correspondence with Haya de la Torre over the period 1948-1960 concerning the Peruvian Labor situation, trend towards totalitarianism and the accusations against Haya de la Torre. Candid views of many of the leaders, press people and labor organizations.
- Peru Victor Raul Haya de la Torre Reports and Statements, 1946-1955 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Memo on Victor Raul Haya de la Torre(circa 1950); Memo to Mathew Woll concerning contacts in Peru mainly Torre's control of Peruvian labor (1946); "The crises of Peronism and Militarism in Indo-American" by Haya de la Torre (1955); statement and resolutio
- Puerto Rico, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Correspondence with Hipolito Marcano (1950) concerning Nationalist Party Rebellion and the impropriety of elections in which Marcano was "ousted" (1951). Also includes various publications and correspondence. including those w/ Luis Munoz Marin; Clarence
- El Salvador Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Includes correspondence with A. McLellan concerning recovery of pro-democratic labor movement and description of junta (1957); Instability in Junta and possible pro-Castro forces gaining control (1960); correspondence. w/Rafael Saravia (1961)
- El Salvador Reports and Statements, 1955-1958 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Includes a series of reports by A. McLellan on trade union activities in El Salvador (1957- ); Memo to Jose Lumus (candidate for president) from Partido Revolucionario de Unification concerning the labor sentiment (1955); article from La Prensa concerning
- El Salvador Clippings, 1958-1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Uruguay Correspondence, 1943-1960 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Includes correspondence. w/Hermes Home concerning strikes in Uruguay, Horres's position w/ICFTU (1950); correspondence. w/Jauregui concerning union situation in Uruguay (1951); Corres. w/Jesus Carbonell (CTC) to Juan Acuna concerning Acuna's labor positio
- Uruguay Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 10a)
  Includes various correspondence. dealing with Romualdi's brother as well as ORIT, ICFTU, CIOSL and other labor activities
- Uruguay Reports, Statements and Speeches, 1946-1958 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Includes Romualdi report to Meany concerning donating funds to labor movement and the weakness of communist forces (1946); memo to Woll (?) concerning contacts in labor movement in Uruguay and their activities (1946); suggestions for establishing an Inte
- Uruguay Clippings, 1951-1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Venezuela - Correspondence, 1951-1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Includes ORIT position paper against political and trade union persecution (1952); Facts about the Venezuelan Dictatorship by Valmore Rodriguez (1953); correspondence. and press release by AFL-CIO concerning whether to attend the oil conference in Caracas
- Venezuela Correspondence, 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Includes ORIT position paper concerning Venezuelan government (1958); Letter to Romualdi concerning fall of dictatorship (1958) Letter to Rubottom of State Dept. re CTV doctrine (1958) from ex-CTV officer; Schnitzler to Millard concerning dispute between
- Reports, Statements, etc., 1946-1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Includes SR report to Mathew Woll concerning his contacts and activities during visit to Caracas (1946); "Statement on Venezuela" (1952) report concerning trade union situation; agreements from 3rd Congress of Movimiento Sindical Independent (1953); list
- Venezuela Clippings (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Venezuela Correspondence w/Romulo Betancourt (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Corres. includes details and opinions of Democratic Conference in Havana; actions con-Corning visa for Betancourt to enter US; and the role of Latin American Labor in world affairs.
- Venezuela Correspondence w/Romulo Betancourt, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Includes report of Cuban Secret Police concerning the attempted assassination of Betancourt; other correspondence concerns the admission by the Venezuelan gov't. to jailing Luis Tomar; Betancourt's view of Venezuelan internal situation, as well as the US
- Venezuela Correspondence w/Romulo Betancourt, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Includes correspondence. dealing with various article denouncing the Venezuelan situation, unrest in Venezuela and persecution under Jimenez, challenging the Venezuelan delegation to Geneva conference; Betancourt's opinions on Peronism, ORIT and Bolivia,
- Venezuela Correspondence w/Romulo Betancourt, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Includes Betancourt's letter to Time concerning the article "Power Stall"; correspondence. between Romualdi and Millard dealing with loan to Venezuelan trade unions and Nixon's trip to Venezuela.
- Venezuela Correspondence Misc. and undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Corres. re AFL-CIO resolution against Dominican Republic, other correspondence.
- Venezuela. Betancourt. Clippings. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Italian
- Correspondence, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 13a)
- Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 14)
  no date; Italian
- Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Includes letter from Frederico Carrassi Del Villar commenting on Carlo Sforza's popularity in Brazil (11/20A3); carbon copy (cc) of a memorandum by SB entitled "Suggestions for Setting up a Latin-American Desk at the American Federation of Labor's Headqu
- Correspondence, 1947-1955 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Includes routine letters from Nelson Rockefeller (3/l4/47); confidential memorandum to Matthew Woll on interview with Norman Armour, Asst. Secretary of State and State Dept. Staff Members (7/10/47); memo's from SR to Lewis J. Hines re "Information on Lat
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Includes "Report on Latin America" by R. Alexander (Puerto Rico, Barbados, Trinidad, British Guiana, Surinam);i letter from Congressman Francis E. Walter soliciting statement on Soviet cold war techniques (6/8/56); report from Robert Alexander (Peru, Ecu
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Speech by George Meany entitled "Inter-American Trade Unionism" (5/10)
- Correspondence, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Correspondence with B. Stephansky, Dept. of State, re establishment of a labor mgt. govt. committee to investigate unfair labor practices in Latin America (3/6, 4/15); correspondence. re Nixon trip to Latin America (4/23, 5/l6); "Report on Trip through La
- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Corres. largely re SR's heart attack; letter by SR to John Miller of NPA Advisory Committee for the Study on United States- Latin American Relations for the Subcommittee on American Republic Affairs, US Senate re SR policy suggestions (7/6); letter to SR r
- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Letters re SR's heart attack including letters from Norman Thomas 4/30, 12/2; letter to John Miller re SR's willingness to become a member of NPA Advisory Committee for the Study of United States-Latin American Relations for the Subcommittee on American R
- Correspondence, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  Letters (April 13) from David Sternback discussing Venezuelan labor situation and (April 19) the trade situation in Chile. Also comments unfavorably (April 19) on special subsidy that Technique is receiving from U.S. source; letters (passim) re Francisco
- Correspondence, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Corres. concerning trip through South America in October; correspondence. concerning Tellechea and need for Mexican visa; various personal correspondence; correspondence, w/Dr. Manuel Ordonez (of Industrial Kaiser Argentina); letter from L. Martinez-Caver
- Correspondence, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Letters from Nelson Rockefeller; Richard Goodwin; Charles Gauld; other misc. correspondence.
- Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 9, Folder 11a)
  Contains memo to Meany concerning political aspects of the Punta del Este Economic Conference; Excerpts of -remarks by Rockefeller at AIFLD Graduation Exercises, 1965.
- Correspondence, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Letter from Rockefeller and from W. Wintz-Secretary of Labor concerning AIFLD
- Correspondence, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Correspondence concerning Romauldi's appt. to work full time for AIFLD
- Correspondence, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Routine correspondence
- Correspondence, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  Memo from Robert Hill to Romualdi recalling conversation concerning Communist infiltration of Castro Regime; other misc. correspondence.
- Correspondence, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  Includes letter from Arturo Jauregui concerning declaration of CLASC; correspondence. w/ Juan Acuna concerning book; other misc. correspondence.
- AIFLD (American Institute for Free Labor), 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Includes newsletters, 1963-65
- CIT (InterAmerican Confederation of Workers), 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Includes Resolution against dictatorial regimes in Latin America passed at 1949 Congress of ICFTU; motion presented by Cuban delegation to 1949 CIT Congress Trujillo; correspondence. w/Arturo Jaurequi between Jaurequi and Romualdi concerning CIT business
- CIT Ibanez Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Correspondence covers Ibanez's term as president of CIT - it deals with topics that include Conference in San Francisco (1949); CIT business; Latin American situation; Message from CIT in 1949 to workers; Canal Zone; CIT's principles against communism a
- CLASIC (Confederacion Latino Americana de Sindicalistas Cristiano's), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Includes correspondence. with Maspero (Exec. Sec. CLASC) concerning articles in Noticiero Obrero Norte Americano on Venezuela; other information concerning Venezuela (1960)
- IADF (Inter-American Association for Democracy and Freedom), 1950-1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Includes correspondence. w/Americo Ghioldi and others concerning planning of Conference Inter-Americana de las fuercas democraticas; remarks of Dr. Adolph Berle, Jr. (former Ass't. Sec. State) at a dinner awarding him annual citation of IADF (1958); Romua
- IDFTU (International Confederation of Free Trade Unions), 1951-1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Includes minutes of conference in 1951; report to J. Oldenbroek (Gen. Sec.) concerning Subcommittee on Inter-American Affairs and visit of AFL-CIO delegation to Latin America in 1956; agreements from First World Congress of Sugar Workers. (1953); Romuald
- ICFTU Ortero Borlaff, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Corres. w/Borlaff concerning Chilean situation 1956; concerning CORVI (Associacion de Obreros de la Corporacion de la Vivienda); correspondence. w/Gerardo Fuentes Gazmuri (Sec. Gen. of CTCH) (1956); Communist influence in CTC; Report on Communist influenc
- ILO (International Labor Office), 1936-1956 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Includes Romualdi address to Fifth Conference of American States, Delegate list for First American Conference of ORIT (1936); articles by Romualdi and others relating to ILO conferences, and activities
- ILO - Ibanez Corres., 1952-1961 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Includes correspondence. during Ibanez's holding office in ILO concerning Latin America labor situation, ORIT-ILO relations; El Salvador; visas for Ibanez's daughter, SR's heart attack
- ILO Monge Corres. (l), 1950 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Includes extensive correspondence. concerning the labor situation in Latin America (Guatemala, Venezuela, etc.) as well as details of the activities and views of SR, Monge, Jauregui, Eddy Alvarez. Corres. was written when Monge was Gen. Sec. of ILO. Also
- ILO Monge Corres. (2), 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 10a)
  Includes more correspondence. concerning labor situation in Latin America as well as correspondence. concerning Monge's resignation for ILO; Costa Rican situation in 1952
- ILO Monge Corres. (3), 1955-1957 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Contains correspondence. between Monge & Romualdi during Monge's term as Secretary General of ORIT; correspondence. concerning ILO-KFTU relations; Arturo Jauregui's resignation as Ass't. Secretary of ORIT; ORIT-ICFTU relations Argentina (1957); and Jaure
- ILO Monge Corres. (4), 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Contains correspondence. w/Monge concerning democratic vs Communist forces in Latin America; calling of the III Conference of the Consultative Committee of the Latin America Secretariat of the Socialist International; problems between Schnitzler and Monge
- ILO Conference of American States -Havana, Cuba, 1956 (Box 10a, Folder 1)
  Contains report of US gov't. delegates to the 6th ILO Conference
- Jauregui, Arturo, 1956 (Box 10a, Folder 2)
  SEE: Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores
- ORIT (Organizacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores), 1950-1952 (Box 10a, Folder 3)
  Includes correspondence. w/Jermes Horne dealing with various CIT businesses; other correspondence. deals with routine matters and one letter to Francisco Aguirre deals with the possibility of Malave being a Communist and possible effect on ORIT activities
- ORIT Correspondence, 1953-1958 (Box 10a, Folder 4)
  Includes correspondence. w/Luis Alberto Colotuzzo (Pres. of ORIT) concerning Miami meeting of Secretariat of ORIT; Report of that meeting; other correspondence. w/Colotuzzo deals with Paraguay, Brazilians in exile in Puerto Rico; memo from students of Cap
- ORIT Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 10a, Folder 5)
  Includes Andrew McLellan report (1958) on trade union activity in Central America; message of Jose Mora (OAS) to IV Continental Congress of the ORIT(1958); ORIT Administrative Committee resolutions (1959); letter from Daniel Benedict (ORIT) to Schnitzler(
- ORIT Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 10a, Folder 6)
  Included report on the ORIT Executive Committee meeting (1959)
- ORIT Reports, Minutes, Statements, 1950-1952 (Box 10a, Folder 7)
  Includes statement on the meeting of Foreign Ministers of America (1951); 2nd meeting of Exec. Board ORIT (1951); SR report on trip to South America (1951); third meeting of ORIT Exec. Bd, (1957);. report of Regional Secretary of ORIT (1951-52); Gen. Sec.
- ORIT -Reports, etc., 1955-1959 (Box 10a, Folder 8)
  Includes report of Andrew McLellan on ORIT-ITS mission to South America (1956); notes on CADORIT (1955); documentary of the early years of ORIT; pamphlet on ORIT-CIOSL School; impressions of 1952 (Feb.) ORIT Exec. Bd. meeting by William Schnitzler; revise
- ORIT Clippings (Box 10a, Folder 9)
- ORIT - Arturo Jauregui Correspondence, 1950-1956 (Box 10a, Folder 10)
  Includes correspondence. concerning CIT-ICFTU relations, Jauregui's candidacy for Asst Secretary of ICFTU; US-Latin American relations; excerpts of report by Jauregui on ICFTU Executive Bd. meeting, July 1956; other correspondence. deals with Jauregui's a
- ORIT Arturo Jauregui Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 10a, Folder 11)
  Includes correspondence. between Monge & Jauregui concerning Jauregui's activities in ORIT over the years and his resignation (1957); historical account of ORIT and the free labor movement; other correspondence. deals with misunderstanding over financia
- ORIT 2nd Economic and Social Conference (Box 10a, Folder 12)
  contains reports, agendas, resolutions and various information pamphlets
- AFL (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Communism (See also: LATIN AMERICAN-GENERAL) (Box 11, Folder 2)
- CIT (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Cuba (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Guiana, British (Box 11, Folder 5)
- ILO (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Latin America - General (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Latin America - General (2) (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Mexico (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Nixon and Latin America (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Peronism (Box 11, Folder 11)
- News clippings, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- News clippings, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- News clippings, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- News clippings, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- News clippings, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- News clippings, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- News clippings, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- News clippings, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- News clippings, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- News clippings, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- News clippings, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- News clippings, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- News clippings (Box 12, Folder 13)
  no date
- "C", 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Includes correspondence. with Bruno Storti (CISI) re AIFLD (1965) with Sigfrido Ciccotto re his recollection of their Italian antifascist activities (1966); with officials of the Canadian International Power Company re their difficulties with government